<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on syls blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on syls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create Plugin Architecture With Python</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-05-23-create-plugin-architecture-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-05-23-create-plugin-architecture-with-python/</guid>
      <description>There are some use-cases where a plugin architecture is needed, I call this &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; plugins but it is quite possible that there is already a word for that. The idea is to &amp;rsquo;load&amp;rsquo; functions or classes that are dynamically created so that you can have the reference to the instances at runtime. I&amp;rsquo;ve created 2 solutions for that matter one that is using the __subclasses__ dunder method and one using a decorator.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple Fishing Bot for World of Warcraft</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-05-22-simple-fishing-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-05-22-simple-fishing-bot/</guid>
      <description>This fishing bot consists only of about 50 lines of code, it incorporates the mechanics of World of Warcraft and some simple Windows API Calls.&#xA;Repository: https://github.com/syrull/simple-fishing-bot&#xA;Overview The bot has about ~99% success rate, there are some extremely rare cases where the bot won&amp;rsquo;t catch it and I will explain why later. The method that the bot is using, should work in almost any fishing scenario in the game, I would personally avoid crowded places.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STIX/TAXII - Complete Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-04-10-stix-taxii-complete-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-04-10-stix-taxii-complete-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Introduction STIX What is STIX and what is TAXII? In the most simple terms STIX is a model of Threat Intelligence that is represented in motivations, abilities, capabilities and response objects. Those objects are then represented in either JSON (STIX 2) or XML (STIX 1).&#xA;Here is a very simple representation of STIX Objects in a graph. Explanation of the example&#xA;The data can be helpful for preventing or mitigating various kinds of attacks that can be expressed with STIX.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Private Packages in Docker Image - Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-05-27-installing-private-packages-in-docker-image-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-05-27-installing-private-packages-in-docker-image-notes/</guid>
      <description>Quick notes about how to forward an ssh agent and other tricks regarding the installation of python packages.&#xA;Using SSH Forwarding Exporting the $SSH_AUTH_SOCK environment variable in the image.&#xA;$ docker run -rm -t -i -v $(dirname $SSH_AUTH_SOCK) -e SSH_AUTH_SOCK=$SSH_AUTH_SOCK ubuntu /bin/bash Or in the environment section of a compose file.&#xA;environment: SSH_AUTH_SOCK: $SSH_AUTH_SOCK Eventual Issues with that Installing ssh in the container Adding entries to /etc/ssh/ssh_known_hosts Caveats Traces of ssh keys inside the image References https://gist.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
